

Portfolio : https://bit.ly/binulalkt Email: ktbinulal@gmail.com Phone : +91 79022 95585 LinkedIn : binu-lal-k-t

ABOUT ME

Software developer with 1+ years of experience in developing web applications. Including 3 successful freelance projects. Experience in working with various programming languages and frameworks. Skilled in working with databases and version control systems. Able to work independently and as part of a team.

SKILLS

Frontend (HTML, CSS, Reactjs).
Backend (Python, Javascript)
Version control(GitHub)

WORK EXPERIENCES

• WEB DEVELOPER

November 2021 - present | Freelancer

- Built and maintained websites for clients.
- Assisted with troubleshooting software.
- Created and tested applications.

• MECHANICS & ELECTRONICS INTERN

April 2019 - April 2019 | Keltron, Thrissur

- Built designs for robotic arms
- Assembled and tested various sensors.
- Filed reports, completed documentation

PROJECTS

• SMART AGRO-POT (ACADEMIC) <u>GitHub</u>

The smart agro pot combines hydroponics, smart technology, and a mobile app. It tracks environmental parameters, sends data to the Blynk app, and allows users to monitor and adjust conditions. Automated alerts ensure timely action. It brings convenience and precision to indoor gardening.

SCHOOL ARTS MANAGMENT SYSTEM GitHub

Software solution that streamlines administrative processes for managing arts programs in educational institutions. It enables efficient enrollment management, arts organization, and staff coordination. it enhances the overall management of arts programs.

• NETFLIX CLONE GitHub Website

Clone of the Netflix website was built using React.JS as a Front-end & Firebase as a Back-end. It's a similar version of Netflix. It contains the home page, sign-in page, sign-up page, browse page, and movie player.

EDUCATION

2019 - 2023 | UNIVERSITY COLLEGE OF ENGINEERING

Bachelor of Technology in Electronics and communication

- Active member of Robotics Club, College NSS Cell,and Infonics.

2017 - 2019 | S N D P HSS, ALUVA

- Active member of Nature Club,

ACHIEVEMENTS

SECOND PRIZE WINNER, ROBOCODING, SAINTGITS NATIONAL-LEVEL TECH FEST. INTER-SCHOOL FOOTBALL CHAMPION.
BEST B. TECH PROJECT 2023 (ECE) IN NATIONAL LEVEL TECH FEST

HOBBIES

READING BOOKS (NON-FICTIONAL)
PARKOUR
IN-DOOR GARDENING